A Guide to the Arnold E. Brown Papers, 1950-1998 (bulk 1952-1962)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Arnold E. Brown Papers, 1950-1998 (bulk 1952-1962)
The Library of Virginia
51001, 51096
5 cubic feet (11 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Arnold Ellwood Brown was born on 9 August 1923. He was the son of Dunlap E. Brown and Gertrude Long. Brown began work in the paper industry at West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company in Covington, Virginia in 1942. He then served in the U.S. Navy during World War II. Following the war, he returned to the mill and became an active member of the United Paperworkers of America Local 675. He served as steward, committee person, vice president, and was president of Local 675 in 1954-1955. Brown was appointed field representative of the United Papermakers and Paperworkers in 1957, and became UPP Region IV vice president in 1963. He played a key role in the formation of the United Paperworkers International Union in 1972. Brown married Viola Mae Gaylor (1926-2011). He retired as Region IV vice president in July 1995. Arnold E. Brown died in Richmond on 8 October 2010. He is buried in Fletcher's Chapel cemetery in Covington.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1950-1998, of Arnold E. Brown (1923-2010) of Covington and Richmond, Virginia, relating to his work as president of the United Paperworkers of America Local 675, and later as a field representative in the United Papermakers and Paperworkers. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1952 to 1962, and includes company policies, constitutions and bylaws, convention and workshop materials, correspondence, labor agreements with various paper mills, leaflets, lists of company employees and union members, meeting notes, proposals, answers, and revisions to agreements, membership applications and authorizations, newsletters and pamphlets, paper industry economic data, trends, and outlooks, proceedings, resolutions, summaries of contracts and fringe benefits, time studies, wage rate schedules, work schedules and job classifications, and weekly activity and expense reports.
Contents List
- Addy, Joseph. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Albemarle Paper Company, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Albemarle Paper Manufacturing Company. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Carbon Paper Manufacturing Company. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Paper Company. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Appointment and Address Book, 1957. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Arbitration - Rules, Policies, Functions, Procedures. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Baltimore Paper Box. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bargaining Economics, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brown, Dianna. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Camp Division, Union Bag-Camp Paper Corporation. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Camp Manufacturing Company. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Cancelled Checks. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Case Book: Selected Extracts From Decisions of the National Labor Relations Board and Courts," March 1958. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Certain-Teed Products Corporation. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cherry River Local No. 423 - Bylaws. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Chesapeake Corporation of Virginia. (Box 2, Folder 5-10)
- Clippings. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "Collective Bargaining Report". (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Continental Can Company. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1957-1965. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Credentials and Number of Votes for Locals. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Double Envelope Corporation. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- "Economic Trends and Outlook" - AFL-CIO Economic Policy Committee. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Expense Reports, 1957-1960. (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- Federal Paper Board Company-Manchester Board and Paper Company Division. (Box 3, Folder 5-9)
- Financial Data for Major Pulp and Paper Companies, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Financial Reports, 1957. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- "The Forty-Eight States: Their Tasks as Policy Makers and Administrators," 1955. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Franklin Paper Products Company. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "Fundamentals in Health and Welfare". (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "Fundamentals of Pension Planning". (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Gardner Board and Carton Company. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Graphic Arts Association of Washington, DC. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Halifax Local No. 425 - Bylaws. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Halifax Paper Company. (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
- Halifax Paper Company, 1952-1953. (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
- Halifax Paper Company - Arbitration Case, 1959. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- "Handbook of Union Government Structure and Procedures". (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Hilde & Dauch Paper Company. (Box 5, Folder 2-7)
- Hopper Paper Company. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- House of Delegates. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "Improving Unemployment Compensation" by Sen. John F. Kennedy, 27 March 1958. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Industrial Engineering Problems - Collective Bargaining Conference, 5 June 1958. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO - "Bulletin". (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO - Third Annual Industrial Relations Conference - Proceedings, 15-16 June 1959. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Inland Container Corporation. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Internal Disputes Plan - AFL-CIO. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- "Labor and the Churches". (Box 5, Folder 16)
- "Labor's Economic Review" - AFL-CIO Department of Research. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Leaflets. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Leave of Absence, 1959. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- List of Locals. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Manchester Board and Paper Company. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- Mead Corporation, Heald Division. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Meeting Notes. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- National Labor Relations Board - Reports, Petitions, Rules and Regulations. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- New Haven Board and Carton Company - Bartgis Brothers Division. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Non-Communist Affidavit. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Normandie Cup Division - Standard Packaging Corporation. (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
- Normandie Cup Division - Standard Packaging Corporation. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- North Carolina Pulp Company. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Organizing Guide - Communication Workers of America. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Owens-Illinois Glass Company, Mill Division. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Paper Industry 500 Largest Companies Statistics, 1961. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Personal. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Phillips, Paul L.. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Photographs. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Photographs (Accession 51096). (Box 7, Folder 9a-b)
- Photographs (Oversize). (Box 59, Folder N/A)
- Postcards. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Pulp, Paper and Allied Industry - Economic Report, 1 April 1959. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Questionnaire - Envelope Local Union Presidents. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Receipts. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Representatives' Council. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Research Department. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Research Negotiation Reports, 1958. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Research Negotiation Reports, 1960-1961. (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
- Resolutions. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Richmond Trades Industrial Council. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Riegel Paper, Pulp and Paperboard Division. (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Right-to-Work Kit, 1957. (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Robert Gair Company, Fibre Board Container Division. (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Ruberoid Company. (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Seaboard Manufacturing Company. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Social Security Benefits, 1958. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Southern Johns-Manville Products Corporation. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Southern Kraft Division, International Paper Company. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Southern Kraft Division Negotiations, 1961. (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- Staff Conference, Region V, 17-18 February 1958. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Staff Conference - U.P.P. Region V, 22 January 1959. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Staff Representatives Bargaining Book, 1958. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Staff Training Conference - "Problems in Collective Bargaining and the Law," 31 March - 3 April 1958. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Staff Training Program - Problems in Arbitration. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Standard Bag Corporation. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- The Steck Company. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Stone Paper Tube Company. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- "Strike Publicity Guide for Local Unions". (Box 8, Folder 15)
- "Successful Grievance Handling". (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Sutherland Paper Company. (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Taft-Hartley Act Filing Requirements. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- "A Taft-Hartley Case Study". (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Time Studies. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Time Study. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Time Study and Wage Incentive School, 10-11 June 1958. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Travel Expense Books, January-February 1958. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Union Bag and Camp Paper Company. (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
- Union Envelope Company. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- "Union Membership as a Condition of Employment". (Box 9, Folder 10)
- United Fund Campaign, 1962. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- United Papermakers and Paperworkers - Constitution, 1957. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- United Papermakers and Paperworkers - Contract Summaries, Fringe Benefit Study, and Supplement to 1959 Economic Report. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- United Papermakers and Paperworkers - First Convention - Proceedings, 6-7 March 1957. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- United Papermakers and Paperworkers - Second Constitutional Constitution, Washington, DC, 19-25 September 1960. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- United Paperworkers International Union - Region IV Convention, 9 October 1995. (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
- United Paperworkers of America - Constitutions. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- United Paperworkers of America - Special Convention, 4-5 March 1957. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Virginia Folding Box Company. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Virginia Safety Association 26th Annual Conference, 5-7 MAy 1960. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Virginia State AFL-CIO - Constitution, 1956. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Virginia State AFL-CIO Fourth Annual Convention, 15-17 June 1959. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Virginia State AFL-CIO - Delegates and Alternates to the Fourth Annual Convention, 1959. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Virginia State AFL-CIO Fifth Annual Convention, 29-31 August 1960. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Virginia State AFL-CIO Financial Report, 1960-1961. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- "Wage Developments in Manufacturing, First 9 Months of 1960". (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Wage Rates, 1960. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Walsh-Healey Minimum Wage Determination Hearing, 1959. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Washington Envelope Company. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Weekly Reports, 1957-1960. (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
- West Coast U.S. Mills - Wage Rates and Contract Summaries, 1960. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company. (Box 11, Folder 7-11)
- Westvaco. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Weyerhaeuser Company, North Carolina Division. (Box 11, Folder 13)
- "What's Wrong with Right-to-Work Laws" by William J. Smith. (Box 11, Folder 14)